<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<recipetypes>
    <recipetype id="1">
        <type>Breakfast recipes</type>
        <name>Crustless quiche bites with asparagus and oven-dried tomatoes</name>
        <desc>We hosted Easter dinner this year and since not everyone in our family is a fan of the
            traditional glazed ham I was looking around for another option that would be easy to mix
            together in the orchestrated chaos that is cooking a holiday meal.

            I settled on these mini, crustless quiches filled with the first asparagus of the season
            and oven-dried grape tomatoes.

            They looked so delicious they almost disappeared as an appetizer but they also made a
            satisfying substitution for those not wanting ham or trying to eat a lighter meal.

            Leftover quiches will keep a couple of days in the refrigerator and can be reheated for
            30 seconds in the microwave for breakfast or a quick lunch served with a simple green
            salad.
        </desc>
    </recipetype>
    <recipetype id="2">
        <type>Lunch recipes</type>
        <name>Roasted chili tomato soup</name>
        <desc>I’m in love with soup season, which has most definitely arrived in full force. Today
            we’re talking about tomato soup, but with a kick! I had a ton of chilies leftover from
            Mom’s garden, so we decided to roast them and add them to my classic tomato soup recipe.
            Spicy! And delicious!

            This could go a variety of ways, depending on the kind of peppers you use: We used
            mostly Jimmy Nardello, some Bulgarian carrot peppers, and jalapeños.
        </desc>
    </recipetype>
    <recipetype id="3">
        <type>Dinner recipes</type>
        <name>Fettuccine with asparagus, bacon, and lemon</name>
        <desc>I always love when those first bunches of tender, slender asparagus show up in markets
            and grocery stores. For me, this first asparagus tastes like spring. I always overbuy
            and overindulge, because I know all too soon, the brawnier, cigar-thick, woody stalks
            will take its place. I overbought last weekend at Detroit’s Eastern Market, getting two
            big, beautiful bunches. Also overbought on lemons, from the same enterprising vendor.
            From there, this recipe practically wrote itself.

            To complement – and perhaps temper – the brightness of the asparagus and lemon, Parmesan
            seemed like a good choice. And unlike the milder goat cheese which often shows up in
            such pasta dishes, it brings more assertive flavor to the party. Which begged for
            another big flavor – salty, crispy, umami-y bacon. For about a second, I considered
            prosciutto, which would have brought a more nuanced meaty quality to the dish. Instead,
            I opted for big flavors all around.

            For as weeknight simple as it was to prepare, this pasta was also fun to eat. The
            flavors all worked together nicely, but not in a blend in, lose their identity kind of
            way. Instead, they jostled one another on the palate, vying for attention. “Taste me!”
            “No, taste me!” I happily tasted them all.
        </desc>
    </recipetype>
    <recipetype id="4">
        <type>Appetizer recipes</type>
        <name>Smoky bacon and onion soup</name>
        <desc>I spend most of my time in the kitchen. It’s my favorite space in this house, a house
            my father has always called a kitchen with a bedroom attached. It’s a large, open space,
            with a fully fitted kitchen, lots of counter space and a den attached where I do most of
            my work on the computer.

            The den opens on to a sunroom with huge windows so the light pours in. That’s where I
            take most of my pictures. The space is perfect for me. One of the many benefits of
            living in the kitchen is the wonderful scents that permeate the space. I never miss out
            on the fragrant bread baking, the sweet cookie smell, the rich stew braising. I love to
            write a recipe while its aromas waft over me. And I snuggle up on the couch with a good
            book and a delicious smell.

            My favorite kitchen fragrances are bacon cooking and onions caramelizing, so you can
            imagine how much I love this soup. It fills my house with the aromas of warmth and
            comfort and fully follows through on the promise. This soup has the feel of a Spanish
            version of French Onion soup with sweet onions made smoky with bacon and smoked paprika,
            and added richness from tomatoes. I particularly love the soup accompanied by a Fontina
            Cheese Toastie or two.

            Smoky Bacon and Onion Soup
            Makes 4 big bowls

            1-1/2 pounds sweet yellow onion (about 2 large)
            5 strips smoked bacon
            2 tablespoons butter
            1 teaspoon chopped fresh marjoram leaves
            1/2 teaspoon smoked paprika
            1 (15-ounce) can crushed tomatoes
            6 cups chicken broth

            1. Slice the onions into very thin half-moons using a mandolin. I you do not have a
            mandolin, shred the onions in the food processor using the grating blade. And of course,
            you can go carefully with a sharp knife. You want nice, thin threads.

            2. Cut the bacon into small pieces and fry in a 5-quart Dutch oven until the bacon is
            crispy. Use a slotted spoon to remove the bacon pieces to paper towels to drain.

            3. Turn off the heat and let the bacon grease cool for several minutes, then add the
            butter and let it melt. Turn the heat back to medium and add the onions. Stir to coat
            the onions completely in the bacon fat and butter, then cover the pot. Cook, stirring
            frequently, until the onions are soft and golden brown. Do not let the onions burn or
            turn dark brown. They need to cook gently to a caramelized softness.

            4. When the onions are soft, stir in the marjoram and continue cooking, covered, until
            the onions are evenly golden. Stir in the paprika and cook for 5 more minutes, making
            sure the onions don’t scorch.

            5. Add the crushed tomatoes and stir, scraping up any browned bits on the bottom of the
            pot. Add half of the cooked bacon and cook until heated through. Pour in the chicken
            stock and bring to a boil. Lower the heat, cover the pot and simmer for 20 minutes.

            6. Taste for salt and pepper and add as needed. Just before serving, stir in the
            remaining bacon pieces.

            Related post on The Runaway Spoon: Fontina Cheese Toastie
        </desc>
    </recipetype>
    <recipetype id="5">
        <type>Salad recipes</type>
        <name>Warm kale, delicata, pearl couscous salad</name>
        <desc>Have I mentioned how much I love living in Portland? I could go on and on about
            wonderful food, coffee, scenery, etc., but today it’s about the wonderful creative women
            I’ve come to know, work with, and call friends! There are so many of them in this town,
            and the opportunities to hang out and create are endless. Keep it coming, universe!

            Today I’m sharing scenes from our PDX Holiday Brunch – a gorgeous morning spent with
            creative ladies, sponsored by some of our faves: Bob’s Red Mill and Tillamook. You can
            imagine how good the food with those two behind it! We all gathered for a sweet morning
            of chatting, sipping, staying warm by the wood stove, and sharing our contributions in a
            family-style meal. Can we do this every week? Hopefully you will be inspired to create a
            holiday brunch with your (lady or otherwise) friends this holiday season! Check out the
            tablescapes for some decoration inspiration – so pretty, I love it!

            I contributed this warm kale salad with delicata, whole wheat pearl couscous, dried
            cranberries, and pepitas. Everyone else brought incredible contributions, too – check
            out these links (and hopefully discover someone new and wonderful to follow!).

            Yogurt Oatcakes with Cranberry-Blueberry Compote from Carly
            Cranberry Chia Parfaits from Alison (Wu Haus)
            Cardamom Rolls with Almond Glaze from Holly and Natalie (The Modern Proper)
            Caramelized Onion, Chanterelle, White Cheddar Quiche with Buckwheat Crust from Christian
            Koepke
            Orange Spice Cake Mimosa and Carob Affogato from Rebekah (PDX Food Love)
            Warm kale, delicata, pearl couscous salad
            Serves: 4-6

            1 delicata squash
            1 tablespoon olive oil
            salt &amp; pepper
            1 cup Bob's Red Mill Whole Wheat Pearl Couscous
            4 tablespoons Tillamook Unsalted Butter
            1 large head of kale
            2 garlic gloves, minced or pressed
            1/3 cup dried cranberries
            1/3 cup pepitas (roasted shelled pumpkin seeds)

            1. Preheat the oven to 400 degrees F.

            Recommended

            RESPONSIBILITY
            The legal principle behind a more restrained Supreme Court term
            2.Slice the squash in half, lengthwise, scoop out seeds, and then cut into half-moons
            1/2-inch think each. Toss with the olive oil, and about 1/2 teaspoon each salt &amp; pepper.
            Arrange in a single layer on a baking sheet, and bake for 20 minutes (or until soft).

            3. While the squash is cooking, prepare the whole wheat pearl couscous according to the
            directions. Set aside 1 tablespoon of the butter to melt into the couscous when it's
            done.

            4. To prepare the kale, chop the kale leaves and heat a heavy, large skillet (with a
            lid) over high heat.

            5. When the skillet is VERY hot, add the kale and 1/4 cup of water. Cover, and let cook
            for 1-2 minutes. When the kale is steamed (it will be moist and bright green), remove
            the lid.

            6. Press in the garlic, add butter, 1/2 teaspoon salt and 1/2 teaspoonpepper. Stir
            briskly so as not to burn any kale, but allow for some darkening of leaves while the
            water cooks off and the garlic slightly cooks – 2 to 3 minutes.

            Recommended

            COVER STORY
            Plastics have shaped nearly every aspect of society. Now what?
            7. Remove the kale from the heat, and toss with the prepared whole wheat couscous.
            Transfer to your serving dish and arrange the squash on top, along with the dried
            cranberries and pepitas.

            8. Serve warm!

            Related post on The Kitchen Paper: Smokey potato split pea soup
        </desc>
    </recipetype>
</recipetypes>